Hello friends, my name is Jai Sharma and
welcome to our channel. Friends, today
we are going to talk about how much money we will get when we add return to
invoice to our policy.
Many times our
channel also gets many comments asking
how much money we will get in RTI or many times we
also get calls asking how much money we will get if there is RTI in
our policy. So we will
talk about this
friends
and let's start.
Now friends, let's talk about whenever we
add RTA to the policy, whether it is a two-
wheeler policy, four-wheeler
policy, commercial vehicle policy, any
policy, if we are
adding return to invoice to our policy, return
to invoice is an add-on. When you
take a zero dep policy,
you can add that add-on along with zero dep. You can get
vehicle insurance whenever you are buying a new vehicle, you can get it even when
you are buying an old vehicle
and you can add that cover continuously in your
old policy as well. So
now the question arises that brother, when we add the cover to the policy  Let's get it done, then
how much money do we get after getting it done, so friends, there are
some conditions here and the conditions are
according to the companies that what
RTI the company is offering you,
what RTI they are offering in their add-ons, so friends, the
first option they have is the
ex-showroom price, friends, there are
many companies which
provide you the value in return to invoice,
they provide the ex-showroom
price, friends, whenever it comes to ex-showroom
price, if your vehicle is
stolen because in RTI
you get money only in case of theft, fire or total loss, so if you are
adding RTI, then
forget about your IDV value, whatever money
you get, you will get it as per return to
invoice, now the
first option I told you in return to invoice is
ex-showroom price, if it is mentioned there
ex-showroom price, now where will it be mentioned,
it could be that it is mentioned in your policy, it could be that the
policy
document which is the brochure is
there online  It may be available on the company's
website. Whichever company, let's say
Reliance 1, Tata, National Insurance,
may be available on their website, and it is
possible that you may not find it available online.
You can talk to your agent or
you can also ask at the branch from where you are taking the policy. So, whenever you
add an RT, what is the first option that comes, the
ex-showroom price. If
it is mentioned in your policy or your add-on that the
company will pay you only the ex-showroom price,
then if your car is stolen, catches fire or is a
total loss, then the company will pay you the ex-showroom price of your car
in exchange for the car.
Suppose your ex-showroom price was 9
lakhs but the onward value of your car was
115 to 12 lakhs, then the company will pay you ₹
lakh there. The company will
not pay you according to the IDV, whether its IDV is 8
lakhs, 7 lakhs or 6 lakhs, it does
not matter, the company will pay you the ex-showroom price there.
Now the second option that comes is
with registration.  The company will
pay the ex-showroom price along with the registration charges, so this option is available
when you take a policy, for example, if you
take a Royal Sundaram policy, then
while taking a Royal Sundaram policy, there are
options whether you want to take ex-showroom
or you want to take with registration charges,
so what will happen in that condition,
your premium will increase a little,
but now the value that you will get, which you will get in case of car
theft, fire in the car or in case of
total loss, will be
with registration charges, now
suppose your ex-showroom price is ₹ lakh
and after applying the registration charges, the
value of your car becomes ₹ lakh,
then the company will pay you ₹ lakh
if ​​you are paying the amount with registration charges,
now let's talk, the third
option is your ex-showroom price plus your
registration charges plus your
insurance amount in it or you
can say on-road price because in on-road
price your registration charge and
your insurance amount are also included, so
whatever will be the on-road price for which you have
purchased the car, then the company will pay you that much  If you pay the
amount, then the first option is ex-showroom, the
second option is with registration charges, the
third option is with registration charges and
with insurance amount, or you can say
that on-road price, if on-road price is
mentioned, then the company will pay you the total amount for which
you have purchased the car, that is,
your invoice amount.
Suppose your car is stolen on-
road for ₹ 1 lakh, now your car gets stolen
or catches fire or there is a total loss, then the
company will pay you the entire amount of ₹ 115 lakh.
Now let's talk about it, is it
necessary that you have to do this in every company?
No, it is not necessary.
Many companies, for example,
Tata AAG, ADAC Ergo, Liberty
Insurance, many companies, or
you can assume that maximum companies
offer you only on-road price, for example, now suppose it is
RAL Sundaram, RAL Sundaram used to offer it earlier,
whenever you used to get a policy, they used to
mention an amount there
that neither on-road nor
actual room was available there, for example, actual room
9  If the policy is one lakh and the on-road price is 12 lakh, then
that amount of around 103 11 lakh would be
mentioned in your policy as per their terms and conditions
and at the time of claim, the
company would pay that amount to you, so
I have talked about Royal Sim, but like in
Tata, you get the on-road price by default, in HDFC you are getting the on-road price,
in Liberty you are getting the on-road
price, in Future Genius you are
getting the on-road price, but
in many companies like
government companies, you do
not get the on-road price, so whenever you
take a policy, when you are taking a policy, you are
taking a policy for a new car, you have purchased an old
car, you are buying a 2-year, 3-year or
4-year-old car, then
you can take an RTI there, or
suppose you had bought a new car 2 years ago and
you are continuously renewing that policy,
whether in the same company or
in another company, you can take it also, but what do
you need to do  You have to check that the company
from which you are adding return to invoice, the
company from which you are taking the ROD policy, you are
adding RTI,
definitely read the terms and conditions of that policy, go to their website and
check it, talk to your agent
that brother, if my car gets stolen, then
what value will the company provide in return to invoice from this company,
all these
things are available on the company's website,
you can download their policy listing,
from there you will get to know how much
value the company will provide you, it should
not happen that you take a policy, let's say you have taken it
from Future Generali for an example
because Future provides full on-road coverage, let's say you have
taken it from Future or
you have taken it from some other company Universal Sopo
and you think brother, I have RTI added in my policy,
I have no problem,
now you will get onward premium, if the car gets stolen, if it
catches fire, you will get the full amount in case of total loss, it is
not like that, if it is
mentioned there that you will get ex-showroom price,
then whatever you do, you will get ex-
showroom price only, you will not get on-road price
there, so  Always keep this in mind
that whenever you buy a policy, always check it,
talk to your agent, check it online,
check on the company's website and download its
policy website or its
brochure, download the policy website
and read it properly, only then
you will be able to get complete information from there, so
friends, this was my video today about return
to invoice, how much amount you
get if you add RTI in your policy, so
friends,
do tell us how you liked this video, if you
liked the video then like the video,
subscribe and if you think
that the video is helpful then
you can share this video with your friends also
[Music]
Thank you